PARTH SHAH

(352)327-1943 | mail@shahparth.net | www.shahparth.net | linkedin.com/in/parth-jayesh-shah | github.com/parthjshah95

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer specializing in integrating AI solutions with products. I have a short yet diverse experience working in various areas like web development, data science, devops, backend development as well as app development. I love to get involved in the entire lifecycle of a product - from brainstorming product ideas, design, implementation, model training to deployment at scale and devops.

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Florida Gainesville, FL

Research Assistant - Modern Artificial Intelligence and Learning Technologies (MALT) lab

Oct 2019 to Present

- VAE Scientific data compression: We propose a novel architecture for autoencoders and variational autoencoders for compression and generation, respectively, of higher dimensional physics data.
- **Temporal data Traffic estimation:** Implemented a queue length prediction algorithm at signalized road intersections for estimation of travel times by analysing data from induction loop sensors using **platoon matching**.

Graduate Assistant - iHeal lab

Jan 2020 to May 2020

• Intelligent ICU: Pose estimation from RGB and depth images for monitoring patients in the ICU

HERE Technologies Mumbai, India

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2019 - Jul 2019

Computer vision: Developed a rapid prototype for a new product, later released as the <u>HERE LiveSense SDK</u>. It involved real-time object detection, multi-object tracking and distance estimation from 2d image stream, on edge devices with hardware constraints.

Software Engineer 2 Jul 2017 - Feb 2019

- Machine learning: Automated detection of duplicate places in geospatial data. Worked with Subject Matter Experts (SMEs) to understand and concretize the problem statement. Implemented, tested and deployed models at scale.
- Full Stack development: Ideated, designed and implemented a drag and drop tool to create domain specific business rules, using the visual programming paradigm. Led to an improvement of 80% in the average turn around time of a rule.

Intern Jul 2016 - Dec 2016

• Backend development: Implemented business rules in scala.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, Javascript (& HTML+CSS), Scala, SQL
- ML Libraries: Pytorch, Keras, Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn
- Web Frameworks: Vuejs, Angularjs(1.x)
- DevOps: Docker, Jenkins, AWS, gcloud, Git
- Software engineering: agile

EDUCATION

• University of Florida, United States: MS in Computer Science, GPA: 3.77/4.0 Expected Graduation: May 2021 Coursework: Fundamentals of Machine Learning, Analysis of Algorithms, Advanced Data Structures, Mathematics for Intelligent Systems

• BITS Pilani, Hyderabad Campus, India: B.E. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering Coursework: Quantum computing, cryptography

Aug 2013 - Jul 2017

PUBLICATIONS

- P. Shah, A. Kanniganti and J. Soumya, "Fault-tolerant application specific Network-on-Chip design," 2017 7th International Symposium on Embedded Computing and System Design (ISED), Durgapur, 2017, pp. 1-5. **DOI:** 10.1109/ISED.2017.8303920
- Rahul Sengupta, Rohith R. K. Reddy, Parth Shah, Anand Rangarajan and Sanjay Ranka, (in press), "A Platoon Matching Approach for the Estimation of Arterial Travel Time Distributions," 2020 IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Conference (ITSC)